Guide to the Wayne S. Vucinich Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wayne S. Vucinich papers
1926-2002
SC0764
Vucinich, Wayne S.
34 Linear feet (35 boxes)
The Wayne S. Vucinich papers include writings, research files, reports, photographs, and other documents related to Vucinich's work.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research. Materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Wayne S. Vucinich joined the Stanford faculty in the Department of History in 1946, teaching courses on Western civilization and Russian and East European history until 1988. He earned his bachelor's, master's and doctoral degrees in Slavic languages and history at the University of California-Berkeley. After graduating in 1941 he joined the Office of Strategic Services and served in the U.S. Navy from 1943 to 1945. Vucinich's many publications include Serbia Between East and West (1954), The Ottoman Empire: Its Record and Legacy (1965), The Peasant in 19th-Century Russia (1968), Contemporary Yugoslavia (1969), Russia and Asia (1972) and Eastern Europe (1973). He died on April 21, 2005.
Description of the Collection
Vucinich's papers were received in four accessions. The first accession consists primarily of typescript drafts of Vucinich's research, largely on the history of Yugoslavia and of Serbs in California. Most of the typescripts were done between 1977 and 1988, after which they were done on computers and are not dated. There is an occasional page in longhand, clipping, or other printed source material. Reprints of some of Vucinich's shorter works (1946-1995) are included. Of note are 5 questionnaires completed by Yugoslavs in California about their life in the old country and in the United States, 1977 and undated. There is no correspondence in this first accession.
The second accession has two parts. Part 1 consists of typescript drafts of his research, with some source materials, on Bileca Rudine, Bosnia and Hercegovina, and the Bulgarian resistance during World War II, and includes Vucinich's correspondence during his time in the OSS, 1943-44. Part 2 pertains to the Joint Stanford-Yugoslav Trebisnjica Archeological Project (1967-69) and includes reports, sketches, maps, and photographs.
The third and fourth accessions include biographical and career documents; further research and writing files on Bileca Rudine, Bosnia and Hercegovina, and the Bulgarian resistance during World War II; and additional sketches, maps, and photographs from the Stanford-Yugoslav Trebisnjica Archeological Project. Also included is an audio recording of a 1966 roundtable discussion on the collapse of Austria-Hungary.
Access Terms
Joint Stanford-Yugoslav Trebisnjica Archeological Project.; United States. Office of Strategic Services. Research and Analysis Branch.; Vucinich, Wayne S.; Bosnia and Hercegovina --Antiquities.; Photoprints.; World War, 1939-1945--Bulgaria; Yugoslavia--History.; Yugoslavia--Politics and government.; Yugoslavs--California.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-137
  - History of Yugoslavia Originals: folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History of Yugoslavia Originals: folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History of Yugoslavia I. Originals (I) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History of Yugoslavia I. Originals (II) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - History of Yugoslavia I. Originals (III) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History of Yugoslavia Original Notes-Supplements: folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History of Yugoslavia Original Notes-Supplements: folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History of Yugoslavia Original Notes-Supplements: folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History of Yugoslavia I: folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - History of Yugoslavia I: folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. II: folder 1: II. Milos Obrenovich 1815-1840 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. II: folder 2: III. Montenegro 1780-1850 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. II: folder 3: IV. Vojrodina 1790-1849 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. III Carbons: folder 1: VIII Slovenia 1st half of 19th century (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. III Carbons: folder 2: VIIIa. B-H in 1st half of 19th century; XI Revolutions 1848-1849 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IV (Carbon): folder 1: XIII Slovenia 2nd half of 19th c. to 1914 (I) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IV (Carbon): folder 2: XIII Slovenia 2nd half of 19th c. to 1914 (II) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IV (Carbon): folder 3: XIII Slovenia 2nd half of 19th c. to 1914 (III) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IV (Carbon): folder 4: XIV Alexander 1840-1858+ (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IV (Carbon): folder 5: Miles + Mihajlo (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IV Carbons: folder 1: XII Vojvodina, 1848-1878 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IV Carbons: folder 2: XVIII Milan's Regency – XX Macedonia 2nd half of 19th century – 1903 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IV Carbons: folder 3: XXI Alexander, 1889-1903+ to 1914? (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. V: XIII Slovenia – 2nd half of 19th century to 1914 – folder 1 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. V: XIII Slovenia – 2nd half of 19th century to 1914 – folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. V: XIII Slovenia – 2nd half of 19th century to 1914 – folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. V: XIII Slovenia – 2nd half of 19th century to 1914 – folder 4 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VI: XIV Alexander: 1840-1858 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VI: XV Milos and Mihajlo 1858-1868 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VI: XVI Vojvodina 1848-1878 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VII Croatia 1878-1903: folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VII (Carbons): folder 1: XXXVII Muslims, nationalism. 1878 – 1914 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VII (Carbons): folder 2: XXVIII Vojrodna – XXX Balkan Alliance + Wars (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VIII XXIV B-H 1875-1914: folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VIII XXV Macedonian Imbroglio 1903-1913: folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VIII XXVII Muslims, Nationalism 1878-1918: folder 3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VIII XXVIII Vojvodina 1878-1918: folder 4 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VIII XXIX Austro-Serbian Relations 1903-1914: folder 5 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VIII XXIX/1 – XXIX/4: folder 6 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. VIII XXX Balkan League and XXXI 1914 Assassination: folder 7 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IX: folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. IX: folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - History of Yugoslavia IX Carbons: folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - History of Yugoslavia IX Carbons: folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - History of Yugoslavia IX Carbons: folder 3 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - History of Yugoslavia IXA (Carbon): folder 1: Interwar Yugoslavia: 1929-1939 XXXVIII (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - History of Yugoslavia IXA (Carbon): folder 2: Interwar 1939-1941 (Sporazum) thru. Foreign Affairs LXI (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - History of Yugoslavia IXA (Carbon): folder 3: Putsch 1941 – Epilogue LXI (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. XI – folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. XI – folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - History of Yugoslavia Vol. XI – folder 3 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - History of Yugoslavia Unlabeled: folder 1: VII: Dalmatia, Dubrovnik, Boka K., Pastrovici, Istria (I) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - History of Yugoslavia Unlabeled: folder 2: VII: Dalmatia, Dubrovnik, Boka K., Pastrovici, Istria (II) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - History of Yugoslavia Unlabeled: folder 3: III: Montenegro 1780-1850 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - History of Yugoslavia Unlabeled: folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - History of Yugoslavia Unlabeled: folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 1: Early History (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 2: Intro: Serbia (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 3: Intro: B+H (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 4: Intro: Montenegro (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 5: Intro: Slovenia (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 6: Military Frontier (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 7: Intro: Croatia (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 8: Ottoman Period (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 9: Karadjordic + 1st Serbian Uprising (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - History of Yugoslavia retype (I): folder 10: II: Milos 1815-1840 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - History of Yugoslavia Introduction (Carbons): folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - History of Yugoslavia Introduction (Carbons): folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - History of Yugoslavia 2nd Copies: folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - History of Yugoslavia 2nd Copies: folder 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - History of Yugoslavia: In the 19th c. Vol I: folder 1: Introduction (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - History of Yugoslavia: In the 19th c. Vol I: folder 2: Introduction 1. Serbia (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - History of Yugoslavia: In the 19th c. Vol I: folder 3: Introduction: B+H Early Period (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - History of Yugoslavia: In the 19th c. Vol I: folder 4: Introduction: Montenegro + 4. Slovenia (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - History of Yugoslavia: In the 19th c. Vol I: folder 5: Introduction: Military Frontier 15th c. – 1870 + 6. Croatia (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - History of Yugoslavia: In the 19th c. Vol I: folder 6: Introduction: Ottoman Period (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Yugoslavia Revolutionary and Conspiratorial Groups in WWI: folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Yugoslavia Revolutionary and Conspiratorial Groups in WWI: folder 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Yugoslavia Revolutionary and Conspiratorial Groups in WWI: folder 3 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - History of Modern Yugoslavia: Chapter XVII (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - History of Modern Yugoslavia: Chapter XVIII (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - History of Modern Yugoslavia: Chapter XIX (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - History of Modern Yugoslavia: Chapter XX (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - History of Modern Yugoslavia – folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - History of Modern Yugoslavia – folder 2 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Croatian Historiography: folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Croatian Historiography: folder 2 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Croatian Historiography: folder 3 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Croatia in War – folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Croatia in War – folder 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Croatia in War – folder 3 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Croatia in War – folder 4 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Croatia in War – Copy – folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Croatia in War – Copy – folder 2 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Croatia in War – Copy – folder 3 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Croatia in War – Chapter VIII – folder 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Croatia in War – Chapter VIII – folder 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Croatia in War – Chapter VIII – folder 3 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chapter VIII – The Genesis of Illyrianism – folder 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chapter VIII – The Genesis of Illyrianism – folder 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Croatian Illyrism – folder 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The Croatian Illyrism – folder 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The Croatian Illyrism – folder 3 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chapter IX – Illyrianism Becomes A Political Movement – folder 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chapter IX – Illyrianism Becomes A Political Movement – folder 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chapter IX – Illyrianism Becomes A Political Movement – folder 3 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Serbs in California I – folder 1 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Serbs in California I – folder 2 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Serbs in California I – folder 3 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Serbs in California II – folder 1 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Serbs in California II – folder 2 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Serbs in California II – folder 3 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Serbs in California II– folder 1 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Serbs in California II– folder 2 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Serbs in California II– folder 3 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Serbs in California II/Index– folder 1 [text, no index] (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Serbs in California II/Index– folder 2 [text, no index] (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Serbs in California II/Index– folder 3 [text and index] (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Serbs in California II/Index– folder 4 [only index] (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Serbs in California III – folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Serbs in California III – folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Serbs in California III – folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Serbs in California III – folder 4 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Serbs in California III– folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Serbs in California III– folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Serbs in California III– folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Serbs in California III– folder 4 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Serbs in California IV– folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Serbs in California IV– folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Serbs in California IV– folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Serbs in California V– folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Serbs in California V– folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Serbs in California V– folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Serbs in California V– folder 4 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Serbs in California V– folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Serbs in California V– folder 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Serbs in California V– folder 3 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Serbs in California, pg. 1605-1777 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Serbs in California, pg. 1605-1892 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Index to Serbs in California (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Index to Serbs in California, Vol. 1 + Vol. V (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Yugoslavs in California: Questionnaire (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Ottoman Conquest: folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ottoman Conquest: folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ottoman Conquest: folder 3 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Ottoman Rule in Bosnia + Herzegovina: folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ottoman Rule in Bosnia + Herzegovina: folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ottoman Rule in Bosnia + Herzegovina: folder 3 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Slavic News Clippings (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Muslims (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Muslims of Bosnia + Herzegovina (WSV) (July 1978) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Smajlovic – Islami Muslimani [photocopy of book, 1977] (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Political Integration of Yugoslavia's Muslims: Determinants of Success and Failure (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Muslims – folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Muslims – folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - History of Russo Serbian Relations – folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - History of Russo Serbian Relations – folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - History of Russo Serbian Relations – folder 3 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - History of Russo Serbian Relations – folder 4 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - History of Eastern Europe 1939-1968 – folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - History of Eastern Europe 1939-1968 – folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - History of Eastern Europe 1939-1968 – folder 3 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Chapter XV: Days of War (concerning WWI period) – folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Chapter XV: Days of War (concerning WWI period) – folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Chapter XV: Days of War (concerning WWI period) – folder 3 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Chapter 6-8 (concerning WWII period) (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - The April War, Yugoslavia ch. 1-4 (concerning WWII period) – folder 1 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - The April War, Yugoslavia ch. 5-7 (concerning WWII period) – folder 2 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - The April War, Yugoslavia ch. 8-9 (concerning WWII period) – folder 3 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The April War, Yugoslavia ch. 10-end (concerning WWII period) – folder 4 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Chapter XIX – History of Uzbekistan – folder 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Chapter XIX – History of Uzbekistan – folder 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Ethnic Composition of the Population of Bosnia-Herzegovina [photocopy of book 1992] (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - History of the Balkans I: folder 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - History of the Balkans I: folder 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - History of the Balkans I: folder 3 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Clues to the Distant Past: folder 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Clues to the Distant Past: folder 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Clues to the Distant Past: folder 3 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Dissident Recruitment of Support: Class Appeals [re Muslims in Bosnia] – folder 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Dissident Recruitment of Support: Class Appeals [re Muslims in Bosnia] – folder 2 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Historiography [Autobiography interwoven with history] – folder 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Historiography [Autobiography interwoven with history] – folder 2 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Historiography [Autobiography interwoven with history] – folder 3 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Published Writings 1940s (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Published Writings 1950s (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Published Writings 1960s (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Published Writings 1970s-80s (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Published Writings 1995 and undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - University of Chicago Round Table Radio Discussions 1948 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Dubrovnik and The American Revolution, Francesco Favi's Letters – folder 1 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Dubrovnik and The American Revolution, Francesco Favi's Letters – folder 2 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Dubrovnik and The American Revolution, Francesco Favi's Letters – folder 3 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Chapter XXIV Bosnia-Herzegovina 1875-1914 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Chapter XXVI Croatia + XXIII Montenegro (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Sabor Dalmatinski 1870 – Decorative Panel [clipping glued to board] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Vojvodina 1848-1867 – folder 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Vojvodina 1848-1867 – folder 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Montenegro – folder 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Montenegro – folder 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Montenegro – folder 3 – Maps (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Macedonian Imbroglio 1908-1913 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Kirgizstan, folder 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Kirgizstan, folder 2 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Karakalpk – Mongols/Tartars (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Central Asia – General (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Azerbaidzhan (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Abkhaz + Adzhars – Uigurs/Dungan, etc. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Klett-Cotta Sonderdruck, reprint 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Chetniks, folder 1 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Chetniks, folder 2 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Chetniks, folder 3 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Serbs in California (I): Page 1-71 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Serbs in California (I): Page 72-155 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Serbs in California (I): Page 156-234 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Serbs in California (I): Page 235-313 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Serbs in California (I): Page 314-394 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Serbs in California (I): Page 395-473 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Serbs in California (II): Page 474-557 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Serbs in California (II): Page 558-678 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Serbs in California (II): Page 679-818 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Serbs in California (III): Page 819-937 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Serbs in California (III): Page 938-1028 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Serbs in California (III): Page 1029-1200 of Draft (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Serbs in California (IV): Page 1201-1326 of Draft (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Serbs in California (IV): Page 1327-1432 of Draft (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Serbs in California (IV): Page 1433-1511 of Draft (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Serbs in California (IV): Page 1512-1604 of Draft (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2006-074
  - Group 1: Typescripts of books/articles (with occasional source materials)
    - Bileca – annexation crisis (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bileca – antiquity (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bileca – Austrian occupation (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bileca – Austrian rule/Army (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bileca – Battle of Kosovo (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bileca – Bogomil (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bileca – Bogomil (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bileca – Hajduks and Uskoks (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Bileca – Interwar period (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bileca – Ottoman rule (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bileca – WWI (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bileca – WWII and after (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Bileca Rudine (1 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bileca Rudine (2 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bileca Rudine (3 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bileca Rudine (4 of 4) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bileca Rudine I, II: Ch. 1 Clues to the Distant Past (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bileca Rudine I, II: Ch. 2 Legacy of the Turks (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. IV Between the Wars (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. V The Second World War (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. V The Second World War (12of 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. VI Postwar Yugoslavia (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. VII Rudine Man and Culture (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. VIII Peasant Society (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. IX Zadniga (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. X Katun (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. XI Orthodox Religion (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. XII Major Holidays (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. XIII Birth, Marriage and Death (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. XIV Health (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. XV Clothing (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Bileca Rudine Ch. XVI Food (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bosnia and Herzegovina, 1875-1914 (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bosnia and Herzegovina, 1875-1914 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Bulgaria: Resistance (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Bulgarian Resistance, Summer 1944, telegrams and reports (1 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Bulgarian Resistance, Summer 1944, telegrams and reports (2 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bulgarian Resistance, Summer 1944, telegrams and reports (3 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Bulgarian Resistance, Summer 1944, telegrams and reports (4 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - History: Muslims in Bosnia and Herzegovina (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Population of Bosnia-Herzegovina (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Population of Bosnia-Herzegovina (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Population of Bosnia-Herzegovina (1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Rudine Ch. 1 Clues to the distant past (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Rudine Ch. 1 footnotes (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Rudine Ch. II Legacy of the Turks (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Rudine Ch. II footnotes (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Rudine Ch. III Austro-Hungarian occupation (and footnotes) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Rudine Ch. IV Between the wars (and footnotes) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Service in Bulgaria (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Service in Bulgaria (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Zadruga (1 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Zadruga (2 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Zadruga (3 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Zadruga (4 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Vucinich's OSS correspondence 1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Vucinich's OSS correspondence 1944 Jan.-Feb. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Vucinich's OSS correspondence 1944 Mar.-July (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Bulgaria 1944-45 (1 of 2) [WSV's article drafts and his reports to Allied Control Commission 1945] (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Bulgaria 1944-45 (1 of 2) [WSV'S reports to Allied Control Commission 1945] (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Group 2: Radine - sources, notes, and some typescript drafts, 1926-83
    - Ancient and medieval history (Box 7, Folder 1)